Hello friends, welcome to Tip Insights.
Today we are going to talk about
how to add a new born baby's name in a health policy. There are two types of policies,
one is an individual policy and the other is a
corporate policy. Both policies have
different procedures for adding a name,
but the documents seem to be the same for both.
So, what is the process for that, we are going to
discuss in this video.
People have a lot of doubts in adding their child
's name, in adding a new born baby's
name, so we will cover all those things
in this video. Today, let's start the video
[music].
Whenever a new born baby is born in our family,
what happens at that time is that some condition arises
that makes it necessary to hospitalize the child,
either it is a premature delivery or
some other problem, then it is
necessary to hospitalize the child. At that
time, we need a health insurance policy, so that the
financial
burden does not fall on you, it does not
become too much on you, so for that, the name of the child is  The
earlier you add the name, the better it will be. It is
not necessary that the
problem will arise only in the new born.
Even after the new born, like even after two months or three months, if the
child is
hospitalized or even after four months or six months, then also
we will get the
benefit by adding the name in health insurance. So the
benefit will be available only when we add it.
What is the process of adding it? So there are
two types of policies, one is
individual policy and the other is corporate
policy. We are going to tell you about the individual policy first. So what is an
individual policy? An individual
policy is a
policy taken by yourself, a policy taken with your own money, a plan chosen by your own will,
either bought from a private agent
or from a private company's portal
or from a private company's app. So
what happens in it is that the
waiting period for adding a new born
baby, the
time taken to add the name of a new born baby in it is
three months, minimum is
three months, some companies may have different options.
But mostly there is a
waiting period of three months to add the name of a newborn baby in
it, only after that we
can add the name. When we add the name of a newborn baby, the
documents required in the individual policy are
Aadhar card, birth
discharge summary and his birth
certificate. These three documents are
required for it.
I have
made a separate video about what is birth discharge summary, you can watch it. The
second thing that happens is that after the three-month
waiting period, we will
give these comments to our agent and he will
process it further. After that the name of the child will be added,
after that a second copy of the policy will also
come in which the names of all the members will be
added in it. After this comes the
second corporate policy. There are
some different things in the corporate policy.
What happens in it is that as soon as the child is born,
he is
covered from the first day under many policies. He is covered from the first day,
but many people are
not aware about this. In the company
we work in, there is
a team related to health insurance, which is called  The
HR team says that
they themselves look after the entire document process
but they have to be told these things, you have to speak to them
for this, you have to be aware yourself,
either you should know all these things before delivery, if you do
n't know then
you can check with your HR and in case of emergency
also you can contact them only
because when a new born baby
needs admission or treatment
then you
can go only through HR, if you cannot go directly
then you can get your documents processed from there,
mother's documents are required in it,
if the mother's name
is Suman then that request will be processed in the name of baby of Suman
and her name will also be added, so the
name which will be added will be
added in the name of baby of Suman only, later
you can also get this name changed, so
you can add the name of the new born baby in both corporate and individual,
I have told you the complete process in this video,
still you have any doubts in your mind
related to this thing then you can
ask me questions in the comment section, you can watch the video
Like and subscribe to the channel and
see you in the next video, till then
hello.